right welcome to a I'm sure to the
eventful idea cafe today's question is
how could we manage conflict resolution
within game B and we've had things
happen within the last 24 hours and make
this a little more impertinent today
Tara or Eric do you want to go first or
I could start I don't mind young for you
because I've actually just written a
fairly lengthy comment about this in in
the thread that underneath bonito
leaving and I mean I've kind of said
this before I don't know if it was an
idea cafe or a lot of other other
conversations I know I am sorry
repeating myself but but nevertheless I
think it's a point worth making that you
know with the best will in the world and
even if everybody is earnestly acting in
good faith you are going to get people
run into conflicts just because they
come from different worlds you know what
I mean they have different perspectives
on things and that's just how it is and
this should be welcomed as an
opportunity for discovery and not you
know not jumped on as a opportunity to
get ourselves into camps and start
fighting each other it's it's it's it's
deeply depressing to me and I and I
think you know in in a community that
seeks to embody things such as rule
Omega you know if you actually try to
live rule Omega not just you know get
together and have a rule I make a chat
once a fortnight but but I mean actually
try to live it in your life then you
know the the notion of conflict
resolution is something that is going on
all the time right how to best manage
interactions right and and whether that
is a conflict or whether it's just a
normal interaction and seeking to get
the most out of it it doesn't really
matter the attitude towards it should be
the same and one final thing on this I I
really strongly feel that if we can't
find some harmony within a group such as
this where we've all come here
voluntarily right because we are
attracted to the ideas of the group
rights we're all on very much on the
same team and coming from broadly
similar perspectives on what the world
is like is deeply depressing that we
witness this kind of fracturing and and
infighting I'm in a group such as this
is deeply depressing to me that's that's
all
thank your Kiera do you wanna go or do
want me to go sure I can go my my
perspective on conflict having grown up
in game a was that when there was
conflict you just tried to get the other
person to see your perspective it was
there was manipulation or anger or
whatever you did whatever you could to
figure out how to get the other person
to see your perspective and for me you
know conflict in game B is recognizing
that when you have humans living in
community they have conflicting needs
and so and how do you identify and
identify what those needs are and get to
and and in some cases you know kind of
identifying what the the higher-level
needs are and being able to address
those and I don't think that you know
and to me
conflict is actually some place where
there is a lot of opportunity for deeper
connection when there is conflict you
can actually come together it's not easy
but it's being able to you know as Eric
said practice rule Omega or you know for
me the other way I the other way I think
about it is behind every action is a
positive intention that even when
somebody's doing something that is just
like I do not understand in the
slightest there is some part of them
that that thinks that if they're if they
do this they will get a need met and you
know is attempting to get a need met for
them and it might be a very
dysfunctional way of getting their need
met
but it isn't you know it is a way and so
when I can recognize that you know okay
this person's doing something that does
not make any sense to me but they are
trying you know they're not doing it
just to be an asshole they're doing it
because they're attempting to get their
needs met
however dysfunctional that may be and so
being able to take
that perspective into the game be and
you know limit the amount of labeling
and name-calling and and you know how
how much I can and and limit the number
of the amount of name-calling labeling
and mind reading and trying to come into
it from a place of curiosity of how do
you know okay what is life like for you
and Trust and and coming into the the
car into a conflict with the assumption
this person is doing the best that they
can no matter how destructive it might
be this person is doing the best that
they can and when I can come in to a
conflict with those things it helps me
to be able to navigate that and figure
out okay how do i how do i walk through
this and you know i I also was dealing
with conflict yesterday not nearly as a
fairly minor but you know it's you know
in some some cases there are times when
it's like okay I know what I know that
this person is going through something
at this moment and I'm just gonna let
them have their have their moment of
having a not good day not not take it
personally and then there are other days
and it's like okay let's we need to have
a conversation about this and yeah being
a able to I think the rule Omega and
trusting that everyone doing their best
or two huge things that I did not learn
going I did not learn from game a that I
really try and bring into game be
whenever there's conflict and curiosity
those are the things I like alright
that's it Thank You Cara I will go next
so we set this thing Kiera and I'm just
gonna mute Eric and Shakira know what
there's like a weird I paused the
washing machine here so then it won't
make noise oh so we set this topic a
week ago after the last one which was on
how to make amends and yet in the last
24 hours i'm jobs sitting right now in
my community i don't live here but i
come and look after this dog when the
family who lives servos
and the neighbor downstairs hates me
like a year and a half ago we got in
this conflict where I didn't we I've
known her for eight years I didn't know
she didn't like me and I went to go try
to make amends and it didn't work she
actually freaked out on me way worse and
to the point where we tried conflict
resolution and she we couldn't even go
through that because she just wanted me
to change like I don't know how to
change she thinks my kids loud I'm like
would you like me to make her not walk I
really don't understand how to like do
it anyway what you want but we would
like leave the house for nap time and
this time anyway so so move it to his
period of not talking to each other I
was like you need to go through a third
party you cannot talk to me and try
calms of resolution but that just didn't
work out and then I have had two or
three times staying here without too
much incidents I've left when she wanted
to and then yesterday she came up and
started a conversation was clearly mad
I'm like I'm not having this
conversation you're gonna need to go
through a third party like I can't do
anything without my kid that's it's just
I can't accommodate you you don't ask
the people who live here to do that
she's like well I own and you don't even
rent I was like oh and she was pushing
it into the house and I was like trying
to get her to leave I'm like I need my
adrenaline was running and I was in
fight flight or freeze I couldn't leave
because she was pushing into the place I
couldn't even get out and go for a walk
and leave and my last resort is always
fight and I like verbally was like you
need to leave raising my voice raised my
boys hoping someone else would come it
eventually got pushed her out of the
doorway closed it and locked it I was
like I can't deal with you right now and
then she said to chemo that was pretty
much like don't talk to anyone about
this I don't I'm like you need to not
come at me if you want me out to talk to
people because this is how I process
things and it was so over the top that
she's like well if you want to go
through a third party you're gonna need
to pay them it's not respectful of their
time I'm like you're right so we need to
come you're gonna need to pay five or
ten dollars every time you want to talk
to me to go through somebody else and
I'm not gonna be being quiet while I'm
here baking during your nap time like
you've went from being a neighbor that's
part of an intentional community but I
want to help you to know Leonard the law
under the City of Vancouver call the
cops if you need to
am I being allowed at 10 past 10:00 p.m.
at night nope I'm not like she just
doesn't like he's a
no matter what the decibel level is it's
not enough for her and she wants every
issue was very much in this state of
like you need to understand me I'm not
leaving I'm like I can't understand you
in the state we kind of a conversation
in this state she's like well you're
meeting it I'm like I need you to stop
having this conversation and I asked her
to leave at least 30 times and she
didn't and so I know it's completely out
of character for me to result to end
with fight but I tried fries and flight
like I said and if you don't give me
leave me with those options the only
option is like you need to leave this
space and it was very evident that she
didn't think of this I was like you're
trespassing she's like you're trespass
to YouTube like I'm invited to be living
here this is like my myspace she
wouldn't do it so it was like she thinks
with me a second-class citizen while I'm
here it's very clear and I'm like I
don't know how to deal with you at that
level and I can't so we're gonna have to
go through a third party and I do try to
it to what Kiera said to be like that is
the best she can she's 70 years old she
doesn't know how to deal with her
emotions that are any better than she
can and I can approach it with as much
compassion as possible but no the
boundaries been crossed
you can't talk to you anymore so that
was my conflict that came out and now
Brent if you want to just sure yeah sure
mm-hmm yeah before what happened
yesterday you know this topic has been
important for me for a long time and I
always advocate for conflict resolution
as opposed to just doing nothing or
sweeping it under the rug and what's
been happening lately is like you know
the mods I've never seen a tempt
conflict resolution right so we have all
these names for protocols and practices
and stuff and people think that they
work but mm-hm
but there is no conflict resolution and
this is a case in point what what
happened was like in in a thread that
was going okay some of the reactionary
people in the group who I'm always
warning about because they're either
trolls or their politics is pathological
or they're just not there to learn
they're there to share share their
opinion I was being attacked by two
people mm-hmm who all named because I
mean
you can still see it and I was kicked
out and they weren't hearty LaBelle and
David Klaus and at the end of the day
you know I was just being attacked and
nobody's stepping in for that they're
just reacting to what I'm saying
in reply um and in fact Jonelle Homer uh
who I guess is one of the mods who she
stepped in on one of the threads and
like I've been told before by other
people like whether it's Jordan Hall or
whoever or Sharon Lewis they tell you to
take it outside
you know they don't want to observe it
they don't want to listen they just tell
you this isn't the place for conflicts
get out okay and in all those all of
those cases and in this one too I asked
the person to contact me directly right
and I do that because I'm an easy person
to talk to and and I said contact me
directly so we don't have to do this on
display for the group right and and and
almost all the time the person doesn't
reach out right and that's fine there's
reasons they might not want to but most
of the time there is no third party
around and the types of people that are
preaching that they want uh uh you know
sense making and mediation and this kind
of stuff they're not doing it they're
just talking about it and they're mean
they're being very exclusive in the way
they behave in the way that they shape
these communities right they want
somebody like me out but they want
people who are actually saying ignorant
or racist things in the group and so I
mean I think that's more ridiculous than
it is offensive to me you know I'm going
to put myself on on trial or whatever to
kind of get to the facts of these
situations and there's been similar
issues in other groups that I've been in
not not necessarily because of me but
because of the attitude towards conflict
resolution right so mm-hmm of course in
in all the kind of intellectual dark web
Facebook groups I participated in and
stuff they're a lot more reactionary and
dismissive if they just don't they don't
want to talk and I kind of expect that
right and bullied at lots of those
groups but in the meta modern mailing
list there's also a couple
Trump supporters and the attitude
towards that from most of the group is
to just not engage right to sweep it
under the rug to pretend like it's not
happening mm-hmm um and in the one case
where conflict resolution was attempted
with actually one of these people one of
these Trump supporters who was quite
aggressive to me quite reactionary in
their politics that guy kind of blew up
blew up and disrupted the the conflict
resolution process I wasn't part of it
but I heard mm-hmm sorry let me get my
camp back ham mi I heard from the
mediator that she was forced to quit
basically because that that person was
bullying her and disrupting the process
right so there's an example of where
conflict resolution was tried I wasn't
even a part of it it was between two
other people but it was in response to
an article I wrote mmm and and that and
that whole process blew up and I could
have predicted it would have done so
because the person was acting in bad
faith and coming from an
anti-intellectual place and that's a
recipe for disaster and there's a lot of
that in game B because we put the
protocols and the practices above the
actual facts and kind of theories about
a social change about politics right
there's we all know very transparently
and I'm talking with Jim about this
later today that game B has an adverse
attitude towards basic concepts like
post-modernism Marxism socialism etc
they just don't want to engage it they
don't want to talk about it because it's
controversial right I don't have a
problem with confrontation or
controversy and where where mediation is
offered I will always accept it right so
we need to get that clear that these
conflicts can be solved people just not
need to not be afraid mm-hmm and the
last thing I'll say you know is that I
think this whole thing is is ridiculous
um not just because like Vinay was
booted a month ago and and and that
whole dramatic affair but people in this
community people like David full
have been bullying me for two and a half
years since I've been in this community
and the sole reason is because his whole
little media empire is built on
promoting Jordan Peterson and the
intellectual dark web and I and others
have criticized that from a good place
from a good faith rule Omega place and
they don't like it they refuse to engage
so the people that have banned me from
this group like David fuller and Jordan
Hall have never spoken to me they don't
they they're hypocrites they don't want
to unpack these issues and that's what
has to happen for game B to be healthy
and to succeed I can expect again the
matter how that goes today
Nolan Mike if we want part I'm you make
up that where it is and see how the rest
of the 45 minutes goes because like the
intention of this one is to say how do
you facilitate conflict resolution and
more of like the abstractness of it
right when you have two parties that are
in conflict how do you then get them to
sit together what if one doesn't want to
sit together how do you how do you
manage that conflict what if there is it
is there a process if there isn't a
process that no one can follow but if
there is a process to make sure that
those things are happening and then Kira
had a conflict in her life I've got a
conflict in my life in the last 24 hours
then this very game be one also has
played out in the last like 24 hours I
mean that one was coming I think for
months like the I think I was reached
out to before to ask how you show up in
this space and I was like on video he
shows up really well he can listen and
and be part and that's where I think a
big piece of it for me is the medium
it's that maybe there shouldn't be
typing from people who don't know how to
type and not read through and be like
okay this is not okay language can we
edit it for you so it is I mean David
clothes actually tagged both of us in a
Facebook
right because I was I just saw I can
post it was like an ex-kgb guy talking
for 40 minutes and he asked us to watch
it and our thoughts on it and then he
actually tagged Brent tonight I was like
I was just gonna scroll past and I was
like no I'm not gonna sit through 40
minutes of watching this guy have much
better things to do with my time but if
you want to see our marks low marks on
socialism you can actually watch Eric
Brent nice conversation on Marxism that
was an ID on an idea cafe then he did he
was like I don't know something about
how we're not receive enouth a language
it was like and how are you gonna own up
to the communism and socialism killed
millions of people like what we did in
the conversation and I don't know how we
could possibly be personally responsible
but hey if you want to have a
conversation I'm down for it I didn't
get any kind of reprimand because my
language was in no way not practicing
the Omega Rule he ordered on it maybe
but it wasn't calling him an idiot it
wasn't saying like I guess my question
is for you Brent like how why can you
not delete that part of it like why why
does it get to that level with you like
why does that come out in text instead
of doing the steel man or whatever the
other side is of like okay delete that
and put this in the most maybe you'll
make a rule way that I possibly can yeah
I do do that a lot you know right I'll
write a message and then I'll delete it
or all or all I'll cut it you know so I
have it saved and I'll do it with emails
too and but in this specific case that
you're mentioning it's interesting
because that was a different thread that
wasn't the one I got booted for but that
thread was that guy David you know just
being kind of antagonistic and looking
for looking for a conflict and kind of
misrepresenting our positions right out
of the gate and you know it's
interesting because what I did reply to
that comment was that you know I said
I'd seen the video you know it's not
it's not new to me
um and I'd be happy to like participate
in an unpacking of that like I was
trying to steal an his position and say
like like yeah I I agree with some of
what this guy is saying like this isn't
new but the whole assumption of that
host was that you know he was assuming
we're just diehard
I heard communists and sorry okay I got
thrown here when my video cuts cuz I
have to click a few things to get it
back yeah so I would have engaged
further on that particular point but it
was just silly and and then I got booted
but yeah it answer your question you
know I do i do censor and limit myself
but sometimes if people say things and
it's public that need to be responded to
or called out you know I responded to
him I responded to him and it wasn't in
that frame it wasn't calling him names
it wasn't it was like yeah I am
anti-capitalist you got me yeah I mean
in this case though it comes from having
experience with particular people in
different contexts right and that that's
always kind of a rais'd mm-hmm so in
this case you know we already had
context with him from the other threads
and it's the same thing for for other
people like like Jordan Hall or David
fuller like they want to completely
erase the context they want to be dicks
themselves in the moment and then do
this gotcha saying if I say something
stupid or if I swear and it's just so
trivial and so prissy what I'm coming to
this space as a serious person
volunteering my time you know to help
people sense make and there's all this
reactionary bullshit going around and
and the people that get lynched in the
end are people like Vinay Gupta or
myself who are ready to put our cards on
the table and I think the stakes are
very high
right so in matters that we push through
instead of just retreating and sweeping
things under the rug and I cannot just
interject one one thing at this point
Brent and and it's hard because and so I
just want to preempt it by saying this
comes from someone who knows you a
little bit you know what I mean enjoys
talking to you I have absolutely no
problem with you whatsoever however I do
find when you write stuff even if you're
not actually swearing at someone or
calling them something or whatever
there is often a tone which I don't know
it has a somewhat dismissive kind of air
to it to me I mean this is how I intend
and so if I'm taking it like that it's
reasonable to think that others might
take it the same way and so I I do feel
that in text you could do a better job
of cultivating language which is not
going to get people's backs up when they
read it you know what I mean absolutely
I agree you know this is something I
work on and it's something that I'm at a
bit of a disadvantage with compared to
other people because you know I don't
have full employment I don't have a
support network around me in things like
this
so I completely agree but like this is
the hypocrisy of the group these people
have to create the conditions right and
you mentioned Bonita Roy leaving I
didn't see that but she's also somebody
who's been like this to me right and and
i you know i'm showing my cards now i
don't care anymore
right she has a problem with me but she
doesn't have the guts to tell me herself
and to talk to me so these people talk
to each other behind other people's
backs and scheme and plan to to boot you
but at the end of the day it's like you
know there's other places for me to be
it's it's your loss you know so I'm
gonna keep trying to participate however
I can you know there's other game be
forums and there's other things going on
like meta modernism and you know coming
from that background uh you know like
I'm not gonna pretend like game B has
been hospitable to that it's taken a
long time for things to come together
like for Hansie to go on Jim ruts show
etc right so these things are very slow
to unravel and I don't care about my
band right now like I I think it was
bullshit when I was blocked
I was I was muted for three days with no
warning and no engagement from the hosts
I was muted because on my black metal
modernism thread
some of these same reaction areas were
dogpiling on me and saying stupid racist
shit and I was standing up against it
and that's why I was muted with you know
with no with no warning and no context
so at this point like there's conflict
and you know if they're not going to
resolve it I will Brett it similar to
Eric you know I've I've enjoyed need to
know you and having these conversations
and there's a couple of things that I
observe in the conversation that I hear
you saying that I hear a little bit of
name-calling calling people dicks
putting people in boxes and and and I
hear some mind-reading that they are
looking for a fight they're trying to be
aggressive and you know I there's and
what I notice within myself as I hear
those things is like there's there's
this part of me that that that kind of
constricts inside and it's you know
there there's this level of complication
and we lost Eric's and the I you know my
husband and I for years we had like
intense conflict in our relationship and
it took us a long time to figure out how
to have those and I watched my head you
know and I watched my husband Hugh very
very brilliant man have like use in work
because perhaps coming and persecution
it coming into the work situation having
this you know coming into it with you
know kind of being ready to fight and
making assumptions about what other
people's intentions were and so when I
hear some assumptions about what the
intentions are Jubilee talked was able
to talk about the the you know this
other thread and I haven't ready either
one but coming into it without making
assumptions about what other people's
intentions are
and so just again and I'm not someone
who who is comfortable saying like
giving people feedback and so this is I
this is pushing my edge to say that but
it's you know what I hear is a lot of
yeah especially mind-reading is the is
the part that I hear that I think gets
in the way of being able to have the
type of conversations that I think you
want to have yeah that's all fine
you know I welcome criticism and and I
don't deny it if it's true um but but
also like my my central point with with
what you're saying and and this this
comes first right the other people are
mind-reading
me right so the people I've listed who
have never engaged me respectfully
they've never reached out they and they
are dicks I'm not gonna be passive or
you know concerned about my use of that
term they show up as being a jerk but
pretending to be a you know diplomat or
whatever and and we've seen groups fall
apart and be torn apart by reactionaries
before I've written about this I've
warned about it and in the past month
the herpes saloon which isn't it was
which was an integral Facebook group
collapsed because of this and I could
have predicted this a year ago cuz
because I knew what was going on in that
group and they wouldn't even let me in
so you know to go back to your point
about mind-reading there is a bit of
that depending on the context on my part
meaning that I have to watch out for but
I'm usually you know I'm not assuming
I'm going off of what I know about the
person and what they were out right so
if people look at the full context and
not just the full context because that's
not enough they need to understand what
was being said what the other person
actually meant and what I meant right
that needs to be unpacked you'll see a
lot of that mind-reading all over the
place and my my my central point is that
you know it like obviously I have to
work on it but the mods have to work on
it too you know if if they're gonna do a
top-down thing it's gonna collapse if
they are following their own rules it's
that simple I guess that's kind of the
question and the more abstract is what
could they have done what would the
thing have been because there is a proce
if there's a process of conflict
resolution where okay take it out of
here I totally understand the take it
outside because we all don't want to see
it we don't want to see the conflict
like screaming back and forth at each
other every other Facebook page is that
this is supposed to be a place for rule
Omega and so I think that that is the
first step to just be like this is out
of hand stop this right now
and when that doesn't happen like what
should there be a way in place to be
like okay we're gonna have a video
conversation with a you know with
somebody who can do conflict resolution
and to parties but then what if one
party doesn't want to what if do you do
that and it's catastrophic I mean it can
be that's kind of what happened with my
neighbor but very muted if you're
talking yeah yeah yeah no just saying
from what Jubilee was saying there that
that feels to me to be a much better
reason to ban someone from the group
they were unwilling to participate in
the conflict resolution process right
you know there is a process there and
it's a goodwill good-faith process and
if you're not prepared to engage in it
and you are you know saying horrible
things and being disruptive and whatever
and you're unwilling to even have a
conversation about it I would be much
happier banning people in those
circumstances than just because we
didn't like what they said or how they
said it because that becomes someone has
then has to be arbiter of what we like
and what we don't like right and that
that always troubles me who gets to
decide is a question that always always
troubles me so yeah I like that I like
that there is some kind of when I go
back to the you know what I think we're
going to see
is that the groups that emerge and are
able to find stability have a particular
ratio of friction to conflict resolution
and this group not necessarily you know
there's practicing rule Omega and
there's conflict resolution and and I
think there's maybe in my mind an
assumption that practicing room
just practicing rule Omega will lead to
conflict resolution and and I don't
necessarily think that that's always the
case and we don't necessarily and it
seems that in this particular Facebook
group there is a necessarily a people
who are the equipped to do the conflict
resolution that I think people that were
that that is probably needed in order to
have to move through some of this stuff
and I think you know there's a certain
amount of like you got a there is a
certain amount of you got to fight it
out you know you have to like bring this
stuff out on the table and there's a lot
of us there's a lot of people who are
not comfortable with doing that I I'm
one of them at times depending on the
situation and yeah it's just in its and
so you know how how would we encourage
conflict resolution that's that's the
thing I've been thinking about this
morning is like how do i how could I
encourage that you know to come forth
and I'm not entirely sure
I'm gonna jump in um just to what Eric
was saying like I don't think
necessarily that other people need to be
banned either like there's there's
definitely reasons to do so but like in
this case I was encouraging those people
to leave the group you know cuz on my
terms I don't think the anti social
justice anti sociology attitude is
healthy or really appropriate right so I
so I try to kind of argue for my own
legitimacy in the group on those terms I
don't think they should be banned just
because they're also saying stupid
things mm-hmm
but uh but to go to what Kyra was saying
- um you know I think a lot of this
needs to be resolved at a more abstract
level meaning you know going back to
something we talked about in the last
couple weeks on one of these calls is I
think we need better briefing and
priming on subjects so when the subject
comes up people have some sort of common
ground and they know what they're
talking about they're not to sharing
random links that are that are easily
falsifiable or debunk a ball and then
that person isn't willing to engage you
know there's there's way too much of
that where somebody shares something
like as if it's proof and it just
creates a deeper argument you know and
related to this race point like people
are you know sharing articles from quill
at an area and this is just a kind of
stalk anti social justice position like
it's very well refined but at the deeper
level its incoherent because it's not
like they're correspond to the actual
research to your research corresponds to
their come on I'm talking about like
real these aren't things they're black
and white they're not gravity they're
people's perceptions and so just I am I
am a social justice warrior I am a
socialist I am anti-capitalist I can
also sit with anyone who's the opposite
and have an actual conversation I don't
care if there's Trump supporters in game
B I welcome them I don't I'm probably
never gonna see the world through their
their
their eyes actually but I can somewhat
step into their shoes and see it from
like their perspective and it helps me
have more compassion for them like there
isn't I mean I get annoyed in the games
v-space in more so when people
intellectualize and want me to do work
that I'm not ready to do like it's like
watch this read this no you watch it and
read it and then if you want to like
give me a paragraph and what that meant
and then I can better like I'm not gonna
do your book report and you're and yet I
mean who was I talking oh is your I
think it was your post Kyra where you
were talking about the definitions right
and I was like yeah I also have a
problem with that and someone responded
with oh you can try these technique I'm
like I have I'm I know how to remember
things I used to know how to remember
things it doesn't work for my brain I'm
good something stick some things don't
it was like try it no I don't need to in
any way I'm good with my brain the way
it is I don't need to like you don't
think it's good enough because like
you're not ok if you're if your language
is I'm good I'm really ok that my brain
is exactly how it is it took a lot of
work to be ok with it
but on gold and so like the idea that we
all have to know the same things and we
all have to agree we have to be primed
so we can agree first that's basically
impossible like we can't is there then
we have to decide on what that priming
is right like what is that and then we
have to like we need the tool then to do
that to the nth degree we need to be
able to say ok if we're gonna do sides
each side puts forth their stuff and the
other side looks at it and critiques it
and goes through that's a debate and I'm
like not at game be for debate I'm a
game be for conversation including
anyone that feels differently on any or
all topics than I do and so I think I'm
able to do that within conflict like
without conflict when I feel the
conflict it's in my body and I have to
deal with it and so I can only control
myself I can't control if they're making
stories up about me I can't control if
they're false on some information I can
point them towards it but just like I'm
not going to read what they tell me
they're probably not going to read it
it's like we'll just read the Wikipedia
article no like if you can't kind of
have like tell me why it's true then I
don't see like have a conversation and I
also am more into a video conversation
because there's more new lots and more
like it's easier to give people the
benefit of the doubt that they're
showing up the best way they can on
video then in text and I don't know
quite why that is you're muted Keira and
I can I meet you
there's this article and I don't know
where my phone is at the moment cuz I
have it on there that it and and this is
something that I was talking about with
somebody in a conversation yesterday or
a couple days ago that the assumption of
the inferential distances distance to
get from where someone is to where we
would like them to be where where we
think they where we would like to get
them so that they can see our
perspective and there is and and one of
the things that it that this article
talked about is being very wary of
coming into a conversation where you
think people are like you had your 10
step 10 10 steps ahead of them don't
come in there with the assumption that
or they'll come in there and let them
know that because they will just write
you off and I bring that up because
Brett there's a very subtle thing that I
hear sometimes in your language which is
I'm here to help people understand I
have a different perspective I'm here to
find the truth I don't know if my way of
looking at things
and so when I hear you say that what the
the mind-reading that I have of that is
you know the right answer and you're and
you're just here to teach everyone else
what that is and again that's my mind
reading and
and and that's what come so there's this
this hesitation in me of and and going
back to Jubilees point of being able to
sit and talk with somebody who has a
completely different worldview than I do
in you you want
I oppose you accept me which makes me
think it's me I'm really okay I hear you
know I would not say that I am
anti-capitalist I would say I'm somebody
who's definitely has concerns about
capitalism and what cap you know it
about the limitations of what capitalism
is capable of I would definitely not
call myself a socialist I you know I but
I would say that there are aspects of
that that of socialism that I think
could be valuable and so it's this so
I'm able to be in these conversations
with you guys because I'm not I don't
think my way is right and so like how do
we go into these conversations and yeah
and I have to mute myself for just a
second because my dog needing some
attention hold on everyone else is muted
so that's that's actually I mean what
Kira was just saying I mean that is
right at the very heart of romaker isn't
it you know what my perspective while it
may be right is never ever ever complete
right there is always more I can there's
and so that sense of I know the right
answer and I'm just here to show it to
someone else means that there's no room
for any new learning to take place right
yeah I mean I I sort of get that sense
sometimes in your in your writing not
not when I'm talking to you Brett but in
your writing I sometimes get that sense
as well that actually your interest is
to win the argument in order me not to
explore not too deep an understanding on
both sides but to show them that they
are wrong and that this is a better way
to look at it is it is is kind of how it
feels sometimes again to me I mean I
can't speak beyond me but you know
that's Kira also so yeah maybe there's
something there
I mean you did actually verbalize it in
this conversation and go back and watch
it but you're like I'm it I'm giving of
my time to help other people make no
which is very different than like I'm
here to make sense of it yeah I'm also
here to learn right don't don't get me
wrong like like I stand by I stand by
what I said but that's only half of the
equation like I'm here to learn too and
I learn Lots from different people but
in my in the way I argue with people or
show up here or show open my articles
especially the articles especially I'm
not necessarily trying to win an
argument a lot of issues I'm trying to
show like I'm trying to transcend the
argument kind of transcend the debate
right because a lot of conflicts and
debates are kind of contrived right and
they're politicized right so they they
mobilize a lot of people towards you
know polarizing on that issue right
whether it's immigration or abortion or
gun rights or whatever the political
discourse is all messed up right so I'm
not coming and saying like look these
are all the right answers X Y Z it's
more like look let's disentangle and D
politicize this let's look at some
answers we've known her true for a long
time you know like like gun control
works like it worked in Australia
legalizing drugs works like it worked in
Portugal like let's D politicize and
depolarize these issues because a lot of
them are already solved right and
there's a lot of contentious issues that
sociologists have been a political
scientists or historians social
scientists in general of unique
perspective and ability to cut through
if people are interested in learning
right mm-hmm but what happens in these
spaces I think is you have a kind of a
lot of thought leaders and a lot of like
the degradation of the signal even
though that's the very thing they're
trying to preserve and so he you know
just to come back to what I was saying
I'm here to learn for sure and I'm also
here to you know to tell people if I've
spent 10 years studying something and
they've never even taken a class on
social justice maybe there is a little
you know differential that we should
respect there and you know tamaak tum'
berger calls this dynamic subordination
like we're supposed to do that when we
recognize the authority and somebody
else if that person's Authority is is
somewhat fraudulent you know like like
like Trump like then we can then we can
discredit or ignore what he's saying
because we have grounds to do so but
there's this you know and I think
everybody understands on some level
there's this erosion of trust in society
so we don't know what experts to trust
and there's lots of people out there on
the kind of the front of the wave so to
speak that that are still just moderates
and centrists and collecting huge
paychecks to just sort of like keep the
status quo going you know there's
there's a lot of equivocation and a lot
of just avoiding the issues and a lot of
people talking outside of their
expertise this is like avoiding the
issue is often is avoiding conflict like
to be in every space all the time being
like we inch our racism and sexism and
homophobia on this and it's like that's
not necessarily what this moments for
that's one of the some of this
discussion is for as much as those are
great ideals to live towards we can't
get to Gainey without dealing with them
we also can't deal with them constantly
like if every conversation can't be
about that every like we only have so
much time and so much energy to devote
to conversations and some people aren't
comfortable having those conversations
and so I mean I have this question that
it kind of comes up in conflict
resolution which is like if you have
something you hold strongly to your
vegan your Christian your whatever that
thing is and you're so forceful with it
that people do the opposite right like
after meeting you as a vegan they go and
eat a burger after meeting you as a
Christian they're like no way am I ever
gonna find are you responsible for that
you just turn somebody off of your
mission because you were so forceful
with it is that on the person or is that
on you and so because it's the very
people who are like no I but I just need
everyone
vegan I just need everyone to be a
Christian it's like yes and you're in no
way helping that happen in fact you're
hurting it you're doing the opposite
it's like reverse televangelism or
something like it's how and I think that
happens a lot in like it's not quite
associated conflict resolution but it
also is it's like deal with my issue
right now it's like and not everything
is about your issue all the time so how
do we find how do we show up as we are
not necessarily infiltrate the space
with our energy you don't like put our
conflict on everyone else and be able to
like take it outside effectively so that
you can actually resolve conflict
because if we can't do within game B or
really not be able to create game B
mm-hmm just go back to what Brent was
saying about expertise because it's a
valid point you're making right if
you've spent 10 years studying something
and someone else has you know they've
read one article whatever in the
Economist or something then you know
undoubtedly your expertise exceeds
theirs and in a sense they should listen
to you I get what you're saying
but in order to establish that
credibility in the minds of other people
it's not just about what you've done
they don't know you anyone can say
they've studied this for 10 years right
I mean yeah they don't actually know you
know they've not seen the work you've
put in they've not read all of your
stuff they don't know your body of work
you know what I mean and so they just
just you saying I've studied this for 10
years and you haven't does not make them
want to listen to you right you
establish that credibility through
consistence
you know positive contributions and and
and and you know little that's what
you've said there is not quite right
it's better framed in this language
something like that that sort of thing
you know little guiding things rather
than based on my 10 years of study this
is what I've learned and understand the
difference between these two things
you've got to establish that credibility
in the mind of your readers in the mind
of your audience and and that that's a
trust issue and Trust is built
bit by bit layer by layer like a brick
wall over time right
I was thinking along those same lines
you know I I have a a fairly deep
distrust of Western medicine at this
point it's just it's not serve me well
in my life and so my trust of expertise
is not like I I'm it's I'm I'm deeply
skeptical of someone who comes in and
tells me that they're an expert if on
the other hand they take the time to
build the trust with me and want to meet
me where I am and understand what my
what my fears are what my concerns are
why I you know why I don't want to
accept their you know their way of
looking at things you know it's I go
back to the you know there's more and
more neuroscience that is that says
humans make decisions based on emotions
and justify them with logic and so you
know when people are having that strong
response even to a even it to somebody
who you know on paper is an expert there
if I don't trust somebody I'm not gonna
listen you know I I think that somebody
is there to and and I will even if
somebody is even if I think someone's an
expert if I think they're there to prove
me wrong there I hate I hate this aspect
of myself but there's almost the part of
me that's like fine if you're if you're
gonna prove me wrong I'm gonna fight
with you just because you know there's
that resistance and so there's an
element of working with human nature I
guess as it is of like humans are highly
you know we're not particularly rational
creatures make decisions you know
impulsively and based on emotion and you
know and it doesn't matter you know I
mean I think our political discourse
proves that it doesn't matter
how many facts you present somebody with
if it if it it if even if those if those
facts feel unsafe people were rejecting
them and so how do we you know so
conflict this is all very appropriate
for cup for the conversation of conflict
resolution because it is you know being
able to resolve conflict involves how
much you trust someone else how much you
are and there's you know and there's a
level you know it's like I mean I think
right had I had had a had this thing
with you happened maybe a month or two
ago before we've had a chance to
interact out have been like yep I
totally understand why they're why
they're doing that but now there's a
there's a part of me that says you know
okay I would like to have a conversation
with one of possibly have a conversation
with one of the moderators and just
understand and understand the
decision-making because I've had
interactions with you that you know tell
me that you're willing to listen but if
all I had the only interaction I had
ever had was the the ones I saw with you
in writing I would've been like ya know
so but having these video of
conversations it's built that trust so
it's an interesting you know yeah how
and given the breakdown in cultural
trust how do we rebuild that how do you
how do we rebuild that trust it's like
it went before a cure talk about exactly
what I was gonna say like doctors are
the experts in our society everything's
like like even if I know but go talk to
a doctor first regs I don't want to be
legally responsible and anyone who's had
more than like I have the flu and I got
something for my doctorate interaction
with doctors gets to the point where
they no longer trust her medical system
someone's giving you a faulty diagnosis
someone's giving you they counter Nick
to each other constantly and these are
the experts and yet you're supposed to
take them at face value and yours to
listen to them like it's the gospel
truth
and then you kills you like it's like
okay well I have to listen to my inner
inner wisdom even if the experts are
telling me the opposite it becomes and
then there is that like defiance of like
you're gonna know then there's that like
little kid in me that wants to like
fight it but like even without that it's
like I'm here for my life I'm the only
one in this relationship of the doctor
patient who's in it for me you're in it
for the statistics you're in it for the
money you're in it for the things that
aren't actually my health and in yet the
part of the conflict is society trusts
them so then you look like you're your
the problem right because you're not
listening to the doctors who are the
experts you're like yes because you
don't understand the entire history and
I can only imagine when it's you know
what I mean it's someone showing up in a
conversation being like hey I have a ten
year doctorate in this I mean anyone who
has education I believe fits along the
curve of like you figure out everything
you don't know and so if you think you
know everything and are the expert on
the topic you're probably not like every
which is my issue with a lot of ego
stuff is like well I'm the expert then
it's like are you are you because you
haven't done this research doctor why
would you I'm one of your patients
you're not gonna spend dozens of hours
researching like I've spent hundreds of
hours researching you're not gonna do it
so yes how do we put and I think it's
oniy that we daren't every gonna have
trust in them we don't can't have trust
in the higher institutions that we used
to and so I need access to medical
information I need my doctor to have
access to medical information my
personal but also more so like actually
in a usable way all of the medical
information so the end mine so that I
could be like yes but my neurologist
said this and my neurosurgeon said this
and my oncologist said this and you guys
aren't agreed this is really annoying
and this person diagnosed me and you
undiagnosed me and it's like you get
together and decide and then you know
people who have the same condition can
be like well no exercise is poison stop
trying to kill us like we are actually
the experts on this listen to us and
every time there's like that power
dynamic in the room of like patient
doctor it's like yes and I'm bringing
all of the other patient
like there are ways to create the tools
that we actually can see more of the
gray area that nothing's black-and-white
like okay I guess I all of my doctors
have done what they've done does it make
me trust the next one anymore in fact it
makes me trust the glass very quick
thought brain I don't know if you'd be
up for doing this but in the spirit of
conflict resolution
I wonder if an approach to the admins
along the lines of I recognize that at
times the language I use is you know
sometimes whatever configurational you
know sorry confrontational and and and
and less than helpful however you know I
think there is some merit to the thing
that you know I've been I've been
somewhat ganged up on at times in this
group as well can we have a conversation
you know out in the open on video as you
know as perhaps the the modeling of a
beginning of a conflict resolution
process within game B would you be
willing to make such an approach you
know humble yourself with knowledge
where you've been in the wrong and seek
to see towbar process absolutely because
like it's not something like that is not
comfortable for me right there's not a
huge incentive but this is what I've
been advocating for for three years
right instead of mm-hmm
egotistical people you know pursuing
their own agenda like let's have an
inclusive out their conversations like
nothing bothers me more in this kind of
sense making space and political moment
then you know the intellectual darkweb
pretending that they're the vanguard and
they're having like dangerous honest
conversations when they're actually
avoiding their their leftist critics and
and so on so like I totally submit to
those processes and I think it would be
good for everyone everything you guys
were saying he was true and useful in an
on topic you know and I think I think it
helps us help salute all of us forward I
think what was the
I forget what I was gonna mmm
close on here
yeah totally lost it
fair enough we usually do this after we
stop recording and actually we've
stopped doing it because every we just
post all of them they're all public but
I think for this one in particular it's
good to have this conversation on camera
are we okay with posting the ck-mb
because I think that it could actually
be a helpful conversation but if
anyone's not okay with it then you can
either not post it there and just leave
it unlisted or private or no absolutely
okay with that I agree with it I think
that's a great idea
all right instead anyone have any we
have like two more minutes left
does anyone have any closing comments
they would like to oh sorry I just want
what Kira was saying the slip don't
break you go ahead it'll come back to me
I forgot I will say by cozied which
beyond the voting thing was I do think
although conflict resolution is really
important and that that conflict to
coccyx resolution ratio is also
important I think one of the most
important things to get to game B is how
to figure out how to be in conflict with
each other without resolution and get
there like if we need everyone to
kumbaya get along it's never gonna
happen whereas if we can figure out okay
these two people don't get along the
conflict resolution is great let's see
if they can get along but also maybe
they never get along and we keep them at
separate tables maybe they can both be
part of it and be and the existing
social media isn't designed for that
it's just blocking and it's not designed
to have video chats and see people's
true humanity so I could put I don't
know if you guys saw an idea cafe kind
of requests where people can post just a
five-minute video so they could kind of
participate in this without having to
participate at this exact time so we can
see each other and connect to each
other's humanity of like here's what
game B means to
and we're all gonna answer the same
question every week so go and check that
out at the eye
I remember what I was gonna say and I
just wouldn't know how quickly because I
think it's important um what I was
saying earlier about expertise
I didn't mean to kind of fetishize the
concept because everything you guys said
was proper critique and so like what I'm
getting at is there's a lot of experts
out there that we have to debunk too and
and I can relate to the doctor thing -
I've had to deal with lots of doctors
that I think we're negligent you know
given given their position and their
income in society but like the way in
which I'm an expert is also as a
generalist not necessarily as choosing a
particular expertise on one topic right
and I think that's relevant here because
I'm aware of my own limits as an expert
on certain topics and will be quick to
defer to other experts if I can kind of
vet them and say and you know use my
epistemology - to use a word that Kira
is interested in now
to understand that that scholar and why
they come up with their position right
so so I can take a sort of meta
perspective even if I'm not as much of
an expert on the topic as them right so
I just want to make that clear like I'm
not fetishizing expertise here there's
there's a lot more nuanced argument
behind that but but it's I think you are
had good critiques yeah I think it's a
mistake to think that conflict
resolution necessarily results in
agreement I agree with orgy but he was
saying though I mean resolution if you
use the word in terms of zooming in
zooming out right then conflict
resolution is drilling down until you
get to the true nature of what the
conflict is right everybody understands
you know why the other ones pissed off
whatever right but everyone actually
understands what it is actually all
about and if the result of that is all
right we just can't play with each other
then fair enough you know what I mean
but but it's but it's done and we know
that now right and you just don't play
with each other anymore if that's the
resolution to the conflict then so be it
but so I absolutely agree it doesn't
need necessarily result in agreement
that that is that is a bit whew
the other thing I wanted to say was that
do you hit it anyway Jubilee was the
ratio of friction to conflict resolution
that the groups that survive are the
ones that find their the proper balance
between these two things right and I
think I think that's absolutely right so
yeah that's all I have to say in
conclusion you know I echo what everyone
else has said and I think the you know
specifically being able to can I be in
relationship with someone who has a very
different worldview than I do and can I
be okay can I be comfortable you know
it's can I be comfortable with being
uncomfortable because then I can't
change your I can't change your mind and
you can't change my mind and can we
still be in relationship and I think at
the heart of how we manage conflict and
game B is how do we manage relationships
and how do we be in relationship with
each other even when we don't agree
absolutely all right and I just will
Eric this talking about this vision of
like compare it be like we can't play
nicely I'm taking the toy away and our
toy is game B and I really don't want to
take it away so can we please play
nicely but I can fight you